乔瑟夫  这是我们最后一次这样做了
Joseph... this is the last time we can do this.
-你说什么呢  -我要回到我丈夫身边
- What are you talking about? - I'm going back to my husband.
-你是说阿方索  -对不起
- Alfonso? - I'm sorry.
安琪亲爱的  那我们怎么办
Angie, baby, what about us?
上帝啊  天啊  他回来了
Oh, my god. Oh, my god. That's him.
-他提前回来了  -安琪拉  你在楼上吗
- He's home early. - Angela, are you upstairs.
去衣橱
The closet.
我的甜心
Mi bello!
好吧  这是怎么个情况
All right, what's going on up there, fellas?
这个玩笑开得有点低劣了吧
The gag getting a little thin?
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
是莎拉
It's Sarah.
有人杀了莎拉
They killed Sarah.
我知道你不是在做早饭  那么
I know you aren't cooking breakfast, so...
那么你这是在做什么
so what is all this?
春季大扫除
Spring cleaning.
母亲大人  这让我很吃惊啊
Mother, I am, I am shocked
你居然知道怎么用海绵块
that you even know how to operate a sponge.
喂  我以前大扫除过
Oh, I have cleaned before.
好吧  我监督别人大扫除过
Well, I've supervised cleaning before.
是什么导致你兴致大发做家务啊
And what has prompted, this sudden burst of domestic devotion?
我表演学校上课那个地儿
The space for my acting school
到下个月也准备不好
won't be ready for another month,
阿丽克西斯忙着准备她的进阶考试
Alexis is all busy with her A.P.tests,
我的午餐约会也取消了
my lunch date canceled...
如果我不让自己忙起来  我的头发
And if I don't do something productive,
-都会被我揪光  所以你给我边去  -抱歉
- I'm gonna tear my hair out, so out my way. - Pardon.
说到头发
Speaking of hair.
你好啊  贝克特
Hello, Beckett.
是的  第21街1777号
Yes. 1777 21st Street.
好  到那见
All right. I'll meet you there.
你刚才是说第21街1777号吗
Did you say 1777 21st Street?
对啊  那发生了一起谋杀案  怎么了
Yeah. There was a murder there. Why?
我知道那个地址  那里是吉星摄影棚
Oh, I know that address. That's Gemstar studios.
那是拍摄《诱惑巷》的地方
That's where they film "Temptation Lane."
是那部你曾经演过的肥皂剧吧
The soap opera you used to be on?
真希望遇害的不是我认识的人
Oh, I-I hope it's nobody that I know.
也许我该和你一起去
Maybe I should go with you.
那可是犯罪现场  老妈
It's a crime scene, mother.
我们是受过训练的专业人士
We're trained professionals.
理查德·卡塞尔  你既没接受过训练
Richard Castle, you are neither trained
也不是专业人士
nor a professional.
我发短信跟你汇报进展
I'll text you with updates.
被害人叫做莎拉·卡特勒
Victim's name is Sarah Cutler.
看上去她应该是昨晚遇害
Looks like she was killed last night
并被塞进了柜子里
and stuffed into a closet on set.
-她参与剧集制作吗  -是的
- Was she a part of the production? - Yeah.
我来猜猜  是大家都很讨厌的跋扈女主角
Let me guess. The diva actress that everyone hated.
卡塞尔  实际上她是个编剧
Actually, Castle, she was a writer.
-编剧  -对
- A writer? - Mm-hmm.
-为什么会有人想要谋杀编剧  -原因多了去了
- Why would anyone want to kill a writer? - Oh, so many reasons.
也许是莎拉发现
Or maybe Sarah discovered
希腊亿万富翁米克斯发明了
that Greek billionaire Mikkos had invented a machine
可以制造暴风雪的机器
that could cause blizzards,
而这机器会将整个世界带入冰河世纪
that would plunge the entire world into an ice age.
不是吧  你的推断是邪恶的造雪机器
Really? You're gonna go with an evil weather machine?
发生过啊
It already happened.
在《综合医院》里就有过  你们记住
On "General Hospital." Look, bear in mind,
我们要进入一个充满戏剧冲突的世界
we're entering into a world of epic drama
里面的角色个个都是生动而夸张
with larger-than-life characters,
他们每个人都有着扭曲的秘密
each one teeming with twisted secrets
和个人阴谋
and personal intrigue.
也就是说这起谋杀案的动机
It stands to reason that the motive for this murder
能写部肥皂剧也是合乎情理的
will be worthy of a soap opera.
卡塞尔  就算是在充满戏剧冲突的世界
Castle, even in a world of epic drama,
杀人动机也都很平常的
the motives are usually quite ordinary.
那对你来说很平常吗
Now does that look ordinary to you?
被害人背后插着一把斧子
The victim with an ax in her back
死在了她自己剧集的拍摄现场
on the set of her own show...
很有可能  凶手就在摄影棚内
Odds are, the killer walks amongst us
混迹于人群之中
on this very soundstage.
有什么发现吗
So what have we got?
她的脊柱被斧头严重砍伤
Her spinal cord was severed with the ax.
而她的肺部也因此充满了血液
Upon contact, her lungs filled with blood,
导致她溺水身亡
'causing her to drown.
我能把死亡时间推算在4小时区间内
I can put the time of death in a 4-hour window,
大概在昨晚7点到11点之间
somewhere between 7:00 and 11:00 p.m. last night.
那斧子又是哪里来的
And where did this ax come from?
是舞台上的消防斧
It's the fire ax from the stage.
剧组的人认为那斧头也许有象征意义
Crew members think it might be symbolic.
象征意义
Symbolic?
当卡特勒小姐接任该剧编剧之后
Well, when Ms. Cutler took over writing the show,
她做的第一件事就是大刀阔斧地
first thing she did was kill off
砍去了该剧的一个主要角色
one of the main characters with an ax.
虽然此举拯救了剧集  但有些粉丝不太开心
Now it saved the show, but some of the fans were unhappy.
你说得太对了  我是大大的不开心
You damn right we were unhappy.
阿什莉·康拉德作为《诱惑巷》的女族长
Ashley Conrad was the matriarch of "Temptation Lane"
整整三十年  结果突然就被砍掉了
for 30 years, and then all of a sudden--whap!
蕾妮
Lanie.
好吧
Right.
根据鉴证组的取证结果  她就是在这里被杀的
Based on the C.S.U. sweep, she was killed right here.
凶手把血迹擦掉
The killer wiped up the blood spatter
然后把她塞进了柜子里
and shoved her in the closet.
也就是说凶手知道这里有一个
Which means they knew there was a closet
可以藏尸的柜子
to shove her into,
表明凶手对这里的布局很熟悉
suggesting someone familiar with the layout.
-也许是内部人作案  -我刚跟保安核实过
- An insider, perhaps? - Well, I just checked with security.
他们现在处于高度警戒状态  但你也能看出来
They're on high alert now, but as you can tell,
警不警戒都差不多
things aren't exactly buttoned up around here.
那监视录像呢
And what about the cameras?
只在正门处有一个摄像头
Only one at the main entrance,
但是这个摄影棚的入口没有门卫
but no one was manning the entrance to this soundstage.
所以说有可能是外人混了进来
Oh, so it is possible that someone from the outside got in?
和死者亲属联系上了吗
Have you talked to next of kin?
尸体被发现的时候  她丈夫就在现场
Husband was on set when the body was discovered.
他是导演之一
Turns out, he's one of the directors.
那你们去给
Okay, so why don't you guys get statements
发现她尸体的演员录口供
from the actors that found her?
-卡塞尔和我去跟死者丈夫谈谈  -好
- Castle and I will talk to the husband. - Right.
这真是悲惨啊  莎拉是个好人
It's tragic, really. I mean, Sarah was a gem.
也非常有天赋
Supremely talented too.
一切都从台词开始
It all begins with the words.
-但也需要演员赋予台词以生命  -说得太对了
- But it's also how you say them. - So true.
我把安琪拉·坎农演活了
My performance brings Angela Cannon to life.
但没有莎拉的台词  我也就是一个
Without Sarah's words, I'd just be
叫做曼迪·布朗森的绝色美女
an incredibly gorgeous woman named Mandy Bronson.
她真的很了解乔瑟夫·福克斯
She really understood Joseph Fox.
也就是我的角色
My character.
他非常复杂深刻
He's very complicated.
复杂深刻  5岁的孩子都能把这个角色写好
Complicated? A 5 year old could write him.
自己明明是个花瓶
You know, I'd be insulted
-就别在那说风凉话了  -布朗森小姐
- if you actually knew anything about acting. - Ms. Bronson,
昨晚你是什么时候离开摄影棚的
what time did you leave the studio last night?
我们6点就收工了  之后我直接回家了
We wrapped at 6:00, and I went straight home.
我  我把浴缸接满水  倒了杯红酒
I, um... I drew a bath, poured a glass of wine,
放上约翰·传奇的歌
put on a little John Legend,
之后我脱下我的丝绸睡袍
then I slipped out of my silk robe
让泡泡浸泡着我的每一寸肌肤
and let the bubbles soak every inch of my body.
伙计
Dude.
-伙计  -伙计
- Dude. - Dude.
-我就是在  -哈斯丁先生  你呢
- I'm just... - Mr. Hastings, how about you?
-一样  -你也泡了个泡泡浴
- Ditto. - You also drew a bubble bath
听了约翰·传奇的歌吗
and listened to some John Legend?
不  我在收工之后直接就走了
No, I left right after we wrapped.
那你最后一次见莎拉是什么时候
And when did you last see sarah?
她在我们拍摄亲热戏之前来了片场
She came down to the set right before we shot a love scene.
折磨戏还差不多
Ha! More like a torture scene,
我被他肥硕的身躯快压窒息了
With me getting smothered by his bulk.
你怎么不去去健身房
Why don't you get your ass to the gym?
下次我们拍吻戏  你要是吃片薄荷糖
I'll go to the gym if you pop a Tic Tac
我就会去健身房
the next time we have to kiss.
我们能回到莎拉这个话题上吗  就一会会
Can we get back to Sarah for just one more moment?
她在剧组有敌人吗
Did she have any enemies in the production?
不不  莎拉人非常好
No, no. Sarah was wonderful.
人人都爱她
Everybody loved her.
她尊重每一个人
She treated everyone with respect.
我想不出有谁会做出这种事
I can't imagine who would do this.
帕沃斯先生  你最后一次得到你妻子的消息是何时
Mr. Powers, when was the last time you heard from your wife?
我  昨晚和莎拉说过话  就在这里
I, um, spoke with Sarah... last night, right--right here,
就在我们现在站的这个地方
Right where we're standing right now.
你们俩谈了些什么
And what did the two of you talk about?
-工作结束  就是唠家常  -那是几点
- End of the day, just touching base. - What time was that?
-也许是6点过一点  -昨晚莎拉没回家
- Maybe a little after 6:00. - Uh, didn't you find it strange
-你不觉得奇怪吗  -我习惯了
- that sarah didn't come home last night? - I'm used to it.
莎拉是首席编剧  长时间伏案写剧本
Sarah's the head writer. Long hours writing scripts,
是家常便饭了
kind of comes with the territory.
她和剧组的人或者演员有什么冲突吗
She have any trouble with cast or crew?
这里的人都各怀心事
Well, everybody here has an agenda,
而莎拉又不得不做出不少艰难的决定
and Sarah had to make a lot of tough decisions,
但没人会想要伤害她的
but nobody here would actually hurt her.
我们就像家人一样
I mean, we're like a family.
那剧组外的人呢
What about anyone outside the show?
不  据我所知没...
No, not that I...
等下
wait.
-什么  -福坎粉丝
- What? - Fox Can lover.
福坎粉丝
Fox Can lover?
一周之前  莎拉把一个疯狂又痴迷的粉丝
About a week ago, sarah had this--this crazy, obsessed fan
踢出了片场
kicked off the set.
她撰写一个非官方的《诱惑巷》博客
Sh-she writes an unofficial blog about the show.
她是个网名叫福坎粉丝的情侣粉
She's a shipper who goes by the screen name FoxCanLover.
-情侣粉  -是热衷一部剧集中
- A shipper? - Uh, yeah, it's a person who invests
特定情侣的粉丝
in the relationships of a show.
这里指代的是乔瑟夫·福克斯和安琪拉·坎农
In this case, it would be Joseph Fox and Angela Cannon,
所以才叫福坎
hence FoxCan.
完全正确  但当她来这儿之后  情绪完全失控
Exactly, but when she gets here, she loses it,
变得疯狂起来  并威胁莎拉
goes crazy, threatens Sarah.
保安不得不把她架出去
Security has to escort her off.
你知道她叫什么名吗
Do you know the lady's name?
不  我不知道  但莎拉助理可能知道
No, I-I don't, but Sarah's assistant would--
里斯·哈蒙
Reese Harmon.
-这是真的吗  -是真的
- Is it true? Oh. - It's true.
-我很抱歉  -我的心肝宝贝就这么没了
- I'm so sorry. - My baby's gone.
我很抱歉  这位是
I'm sorry. This is, um,
这位是莎拉的妈妈  歌莉娅·钱伯斯
this is Sarah's mom, Gloria Chambers.
贝克特探长负责调查莎拉的谋杀案
Detective Beckett is investigating Sarah's murder.
老天不长眼啊
It's so unfair.
我刚刚找到她  她却撒手人寰
I just got her back, and now she's gone.
钱伯斯夫人  你和莎拉母女分离吗
Mrs. Chambers, were the two of you estranged?
我们分开很多年了
We had been for years.
我年轻的时候把她送去领养了
I gave her up for adoption when I was young.
什么样的恶人会做得出这种事啊
What kind of monster would do this?
我们暂时还不知道  但我们会尽我们所能
We don't know just yet, but we are gonna do
将他绳之于法
everything we can to bring them to justice.
你最好如此  不然我要起诉市政府
You'd better, or I will sue the entire city
赔偿我的损失
for every nickel it's worth.
心情沮丧我能理解
Well, I understand being upset,
但起诉市政府  太夸张了吧
but threatening to sue?
每个人表达自己的悲愤的方式都有所不同
Yeah, well, everybody processes their grief differently.
没错  除非她是一个见钱眼开的机会主义者
Yes, unless she's a gold-digging opportunist
图谋不轨重新进入自己女儿的生活
who's insinuated herself back into her daughter's life
只因自己需要进行心脏移植手术
because she's in need of a heart transplant,
而莎拉是唯一的匹配者
and Sarah was the only compatible donator.
是啊  《诱惑巷》的情节还差不多
Sure, maybe in Temptation Lane
在现实世界中太扯了
Not in the real world.
-对了 福坎哈  -嗯
- Uh, speaking of which , FoxCan? - Mm-hmm.
乔瑟夫·福克斯和安琪拉·坎农
Joseph Fox and Angela Cannon--
你怎么知道他们的名字的
how did you know their names?
有位警官给我做过案情摘要
Uh, one of the uniforms briefed me.
那情侣粉呢  八卦恋情的粉丝
Oh. And shippers-- relationship fans?
-拜托  卡塞尔  我有读书的  -好吧
- Castle, I do read, you know? - Cool.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你是里斯·哈蒙吗
Are you Reese Harmon?
福坎粉丝的真名叫凯莉·爱德华兹
FoxCanLover's real name is Carrie Edwards.
她在莎拉出资的一个文学慈善活动上
She won the set visit from a literacy charity
花了1000美元得到了参观片场的机会
that sarah supported. She paid $1,000 for it.
一开始一切都正常  但当她见到了莎拉
Everything was fine at first, but when she saw Sarah,
她便对莎拉死缠烂打  开始大喊大叫
she got in her face and started yelling,
"你毁了一切"
"You ruined everything."
她给莎拉发过恐吓信吗
Did she ever send Sarah any threatening letters,
我是指你记录在案的
anything that you might have on file?
没有  但她在她的博客上写过不少很恶毒的话
No, but she did write some pretty awful things on her blog.
我找给你看
I'll show you that.
如果莎拉工作到很晚  你为什么不留在这
If Sarah was working late, why weren't you here?
你是她的助手啊
You--you are her assistant?
我通常会留下  但莎拉不让
I usually stay, but Sarah wouldn't let me.
-为什么不呢  -她热衷于帮助年轻的编剧
- Why not? - One of her passions was helping young writers.
她在电视台奖学金计划给我留了个位置
She got me a position at the network fellowship program.
我们昨晚有一个联谊会
We had a mixer last night.
她本应该到场  但是她却没有露面
She was supposed to come, but... she never showed.
你最后一次看见她是什么时候
When was the last time you saw her?
六点半左右
Around 6:30.
给她拿了咖啡和烤饼
Brought her her coffee and scone.
找到了  上周参观片场那天
Here it is. Last week, the day of the set visit,
看看她都写了什么
look at what she wrote.
"成功来到片场  但没能完成使命"
"Made it onto the set, but didn't complete the mission."
看看最近这一条留言
Look at the most recent post.
"上次我失败了  这次我会成功"
"Last time, I failed. This time I will succeed."
"她一直在伤我们这些忠实影迷的心
"She's been stabbing us loyal fans in the back.
该是我们去伤害一下她的时候了"
Now it's our turn to take her down..."
"是时候给她一斧头了"
"It's time to give her the axe."
翻译：Cath.k  咖啡十三  深深  大卫熊  vero  小熊嘟嘟
时间轴：小穗   好油油    校对：大卫熊   后期&总监：瓜瓜
-她死了  -嗯
- She's dead? - Yeah.
莎拉·卡特勒真的死了
Sarah Cutler's dead?
史上最棒的新闻了
That's the best news ever.
我能发条微博吗
Can I send a quick tweet?
不成
Not cool?
-那我等下吧  -昨晚忍着
- I'll wait. - Must have been
没更新博客把你憋坏了吧
difficult not to blog about it last night.
我怎么会知道啊
Yeah. How would I know?
等下
Wait.
你们觉得我和这件事有关系吗
You guys think I had something to do with this?
你博客上的言辞很明显地
Well, I mean, your blog clearly spells out
表达出你要置莎拉于死地的决心
your determination to take out Sarah.
但人人都爱在网上放狠话
But everybody talks tough on the internet.
你在她被斧头砍死的那天
You wrote, "It's time to give her the axe"
留言说"是时候给她一斧头了"
the day she was killed with an axe.
这个我可以解释
Okay, now I can explain this.
我们已经想出来了
We already figured it out.
你买了片场参观之旅来接近莎拉
You bought the set visit to get closer to Sarah.
你中途被赶了出去
Your visit was cut short.
昨晚  你在大家都离开之后返回这里
You came back last night when no one was around
然后你突然想起摄影棚里有一把斧头
and then you remembered, there's an axe on the soundstage.
不不  我去参观是因为
No, no, no. I bought the set visit
她被坎方索粉给说动摇了
because she was being swayed by the CanFonsos.
谁
Who?
坎方索粉  我们的对头
The CanFonsos-- The opposition.
他们认为安琪拉·坎农
They believe that Angela Cannon
应该和阿方索·多明戈斯在一起
should be together with Alfonso Dominguez.
我试着说服她
I was trying to convince her
-安琪拉和乔瑟夫才是一对儿  -用斧头说服吗
- that Angela belongs with Joseph. - With an axe?
是啊
Yes.
等下  不是的
Wait. No.
我在发起一项抗议活动  我们准备
I was organizing a protest, okay? We were gonna send
给电视台的头儿寄去一大堆斧头
a whole bunch of axes to the head of the network,
要求炒掉莎拉
demanding that Sarah be fired.
我让我博客上所有人都这么做
I've got everybody on my web site doing it.
我们想让他们知道莎拉正在毁了这部剧
We want them to know that we think Sarah's ruining the show.
昨晚7点到11点你在哪里
Where were you last night between 7:00 and 11:00?
我和其他福坎粉丝在一起聊天
I was chatting with the other FoxCans.
我猜下  一个人吧
Wild guess--alone?
不  我可以证明  玛丽和丹尼斯也在家
No. No, and I can prove it. Mary and Dennis were home.
那些人是你的室友吗
And those are your roommates?
不  是我老爸老妈
No. My parents.
我觉得她连门都出不了
I just don't see that girl swinging an axe,
更别提挥斧子了
let alone leaving her house.
怎么  有凶杀倾向的粉丝对你来说不够肥皂吗
What's the matter, homicidal fan not soapy enough for you?
当你说肥皂的时候
You know, when you say soapy,
-我意淫了  -卡塞尔  集中精力
- I conjure up images - Castle, focus.
-我很集中  -集中到我们的嫌疑犯上
- I am. - On our suspect.
你看到她有多狂热了
I mean, you saw how obsessive she was.
她对这些虚构的情侣关系几近痴迷
She invests in these fictional relationships.
她在意安琪拉是否会回到阿方索身边
She cares if Angela is gonna get back together with Alfonso,
-玛格丽特能否战胜癌症恐慌  -我的天啊
- if Marguerite's gonna survive her cancer scare - Oh, my god.
怎么了
What?
你看《诱惑巷》
You watch "Temptation Lane."
啥
What?
才没有
No.
没有人说起过
No one said anything...
玛格丽特的癌症恐慌
about Marguerite's cancer scare.
你对情侣粉了如指掌  还知道福坎粉丝
You know a lot about shipper, you know about FoxCans.
你是个粉丝  一个《诱惑巷》的死忠粉丝
You are a fan--a big, fat "Temptation Lane" Fan.
好吧  可能我看过一两次
Okay, maybe I watched it like once or twice.
不过这很是不符合你的性格啊
It's just so delightfully not you.
某个熟知《综合医院》剧情的人
So says the guy who rattles off plot points
还好意思说我
from "General hospital."
那完全是两码事
Oh, that is completely different.
-那是为了研究  -什么研究
- That is for research. - What was for research?
-没什么  -没什么
- Nothing. - Nothing.
玛丽和丹尼斯证实
Mary and Dennis confirm
那个博客小妞整晚都呆在自己的房间里
that blogger chick was in her room all night.
演员和剧组人员那边有什么情况
What about the cast and crew?
目前为止  他们的不在场证明都是成立的
So far, all their alibis checked out.
但我在仔细调查莎拉的日程表时
But I was looking over Sarah's schedule.
发现上周有几个约会
Last week, there were a couple of appointments
只标注了M
that just say "M",
谋杀前一天有一次
and there was another one the day before the murder,
明天还跟M有约
then one scheduled for tomorrow.
-那又如何  -这不是她的助手安排的约会
- So? - So her assistant didn't schedule these,
也就是说是私事
which means it was personal,
而且她的丈夫
and her husband didn't
-也不知道这些约会  -鉴于莎拉工作那么忙
- know about them either. - With Sarah's workload,
还要挤出时间  说明这是很重要的约会
it must have been important for her to make time.
没错  而且她的丈夫和助手都说
Exactly, and her husband and assistant both say that
她每次赴约回来后  心情都十分沮丧
when she came back from these appointments, she was upset.
那好  看看我们能从这里找到什么线索
All right, let's see what we can dig up from that.
-贝克特  -你在公寓里发现什么没
- Hey, Beckett. - Hey. What'd you find at the apartment?
她丈夫的东西
Her husband's stuff.
他的衣服全不见了  浴室也只有她的东西
His clothes are gone, and only her stuff is in the bathroom,
我和看门人谈过  他说
so I talked to the doorman, and he said
文斯将近两个多月没住在那儿了
That Vince hasn't lived there in almost two months.
他们分居了
They've been separated.
有意思  他之前可没提这回事
Funny he didn't mention that earlier.
看来有人在《诱惑巷》藏了什么东西
Looks like someone's hiding something on "Temptation Lane."
我知道如果告诉你们我的婚姻出现了问题
Look, I knew if I told you that my marriage was in trouble
我就会成为头号嫌疑人
that I would be suspect number one.
也许  但现在我们知道你撒了谎
Maybe, but now that we know that you lied,
你就更可疑了
it makes you look even worse.
你们为什么分居
Why did you separate?
自从莎拉成了首席编剧  一切都变了
Everything changed after Sarah got the big promotion.
我想和自己的妻子待一会儿
If I wanted to spend time with my own wife,
还得先预约
I had to schedule an appointment.
我受不了  所以我就搬出去了
It wasn't working, so I moved out.
这个故事还有另一个版本
You know, there's another version of this story
那就是你妻子把你赶出家门  并要求离婚
where your wife kicked you out, and then she demanded a divorce.
把她杀死你就不必担心
Hmm. Only this way, you don't have to worry
-她会分你的财产了  -我没杀我妻子
- about splitting your assets.  - I didn't kill my wife.
那她被害那晚你到底在哪儿
Well, then where were you the night that she was killed?
我在旅馆
I was at the hotel.
这里收工  我就去了旅馆
I went there immediately after we rapped here.
有人能证明吗
And can anyone vouch for that?
快说吧  文斯
Come on, Vince.
说你是一个人
Tell us you were alone.
这样我们逮捕你也省点儿事
It'll make arresting you that much easier.
我
I, um...
我不是  独自一人
I wasn't... alone.
另一个人是谁
I'm gonna need a name.
曼迪·布朗森
Mandy Bronson.
Mandy Bronson?
饰演《欲望巷》里的安琪拉·坎农那个吗
As in Angela Cannon, as in star of "Temptation lane"?
是的  就是那个曼迪·布朗森
Yes, that Mandy Bronson.
我就随口问问
Just checking.
她在那儿过夜了吗
Did she stay the night?
没有  我们定了客房服务  然后
No. We ordered room service, and, um...
大概7点钟  她收到莎拉的邮件
About 7:00, she got an e-mail from Sarah
然后就走了
and she went running off.
也就是说你妻子被杀害的那晚
So the night that your wife was killed,
她发过邮件给你的情人
she e-mailed your mistress,
你觉得这不值一提吗
and you didn't think that that was important to mention?
这又不是什么大事
It wasn't a big deal.
我问过曼迪了  她说有些新剧本
I asked Mandy about it. She got some new script pages
莎拉想让她熟悉一下
that Sarah wanted her to look over,
于是她就回家去记台词了
so she went home to memorize them.
后半夜你是一个人吗
Were you alone the rest of the night?
是  是的  我打开小冰箱
Yes. Yes. I cracked the minibar,
看了付费电视  你可以去查
I ordered pay-per-view. You can check.
我会的
I will.
-不可能是她老公  -但他有动机
- It can't be the husband.  - Well, he's got motive.
不错  但婚姻都不保了  为了谋财吗
Yeah, but marriage on the rocks, killing for money?
-这也太  -常见了
- That's just so--  - Ordinary.
我们应该注意的是曼迪·布朗森
We need to focus on Mandy Bronson--
跟死者丈夫干柴烈火  导致别人婚姻
Home-wrecking diva engaged in a torrid affair
不和睦的跋扈女主角
with the victim's husband.
在莎拉被害的当天傍晚
She fled their illicit love nest
安琪拉在收到神秘邮件之后
after a mysterious e-mail from Sarah
逃离了他们偷情的爱巢
on the eve of her murder.
是啊  但我们还不知道是否有那封邮件
Yeah, but we don't even know if there was an e-mail.
我是说文森特有可能在撒谎  不过你说得对
I mean, Vincent could've been lying. But you are right.
曼迪·布朗森确实需要解释一下
Mandy Bronson does have some explaining to do.
-埃斯蕾妮  -什么
- "Esplanie."  - What?
蕾妮和埃斯波西托啊  就像福坎
Lanie and Esposito. Like FoxCan.
我们可以叫他们埃斯蕾妮  不是很妙吗
We can call them Esplanie, which is perfect
因为他们老是在做"解释"
because they're always esplaining things.
老妈
Mother?
-嗨  -玛莎  真没想到啊
- Hi.  - Martha, what a surprise.
是啊  各种没想到啊
Yes, what an unexpected surprise.
-你来这里做什么  -哀悼啊
- What are you doing here?  - Grieving.
你都不认识被害人
You didn't even know the victim.
亲爱的  这样的一部剧痛失编剧
Darling, a loss for a show like this
对于所有参与过这部剧的人来说都是很悲痛的
is a loss for anyone who was ever part of its history.
再说
And...
我觉得我能帮上忙
I think I can be of help here.
我可以做你们的内线
I think I could be your inside source
探查一下这里到底有什么内幕
and get the scoop on what's really going on here.
哎呦喂  从兰斯·哈斯丁下手再好不过了
Oh, ho ho. And what better place to start than Lance Hastings?
你认识他吗
You know him?
他是我30年的老相好  剧里
He was my love interest 30 years ago, onscreen...
剧外也是
and off.
在我扮演的角色嫁给他饰演的乔瑟夫·福克斯之后
After my character married his character, Joseph Fox,
她被绑架  活埋
she was kidnapped, buried alive,
和熊一起困在山洞里  再被绑架
trapped in a cave with bears, kidnapped again,
然后被劫持  关在巴黎的下水道
and held hostage in the sewers of Paris.
-你演了多久啊  -三个星期
- How long were you on the show?  - Three weeks.
我得走了  失陪
Gotta go. Excuse me.
我妈真是给"显而易见"一词做了新的诠释啊
My mother gives new meaning to the word "transparent."
这是她的邮箱  你们想找什么
There's her account. What are you looking for?
莎拉死之前发的一封邮件
An e-mail that Sarah sent before she died.
这个
There it is.
"马上来办公室见我"
"Meet me at the office asap."
那晚莎拉让曼迪到这里来见她
So Sarah had Mandy meet her here that night.
你认为是她发现了他们的奸情
You think she found out about the affair,
打算和她对质吗
planned to confront her?
我不知道  有附件
I don't know. There's an attachment.
是下一集的剧本
Oh, it's a script for an upcoming episode.
角色们在潘普洛纳[西班牙城市]度假
The characters are vacationing in Pamplona.
-天呐  -我的天啊
- Oh, my god.  - Oh, my god.
曼迪·布朗森的角色在跟公牛奔跑时
Mandy Bronson's character is gored to death
被戳死了
while running with the bulls.
莎拉叫曼迪来
Sarah brought her here
是想告诉她  她被写死了
to tell Mandy she was writing her off the show.
看来是曼迪先把她给解决了
Looks like Mandy wrote her off first.
卡塞尔  过来  过来
Castle. Come here. Come here. Come here.
我知道她是谋杀案疑犯
I know she's a murder suspect,
但必须承认  她太火辣了
but you gotta admit, she is smokin' hot.
同意  正点到死者的导演丈夫
Agreed. So hot, in fact, it led to a torrid affair
跟她偷情
with Sarah's director husband.
莎拉发现了
Sarah found out about it,
打算把曼迪的角色写死
decided to kill off Mandy's character.
没有比这更肥皂的剧情了
Doesn't get any soapier than that.
很显然你没看过《娇小玲珑》
Well, obviously you haven't seen Chiquitas.
-香蕉吗  -不是  西班牙语肥皂剧
- As in bananas? - No, as in the telenovela.
小时候和外婆总是一起看那部剧
I used to watch it growing up with my grandmother.
兄弟  其中有一集加布里埃拉发现
Bro, there was this one episode where Gabriela discovered that
她丈夫和她那邪恶的胞妹特雷西塔上床
her husband was sleeping with her evil twin sister Teresita,
结果后来才发现
only to later find out that she had
她有多重人格分裂症
multiple personality disorder.
等等  那能算是出轨吗
Wait. Does that even qualify as cheating?
-老兄  -怎么了
- Dude.  - What?
别瞎分析
Don't overthink it.
布朗森小姐  我很好奇
Ms. Bronson, I'm curious how you felt
当你发现
when you found out
莎拉要把你的角色写死时你是什么感觉
that Sarah was gonna kill off your character.
杀了我的角色  太可笑了
Kill off my character? That's ridiculous.
收视率提升都是因为我
I'm the reason the ratings were up.
那她为什么要写
Well, then why did she write this scene
安琪拉·坎农不幸被公牛戳死这一幕呢
where Angela Cannon has an unfortunate encounter with a bull?
莎拉可能给这个剧的每一个角色
Sarah probably writes a death scene
都写好了一个死亡场景
for every character on the show...
为了让演员不要太嚣张
to keep the actors in line.
她在自己被害那晚才写了那些剧本
She wrote those particular pages the night that she was murdered
而当时你和她丈夫在一起
while you were with her husband.
他说你一收到
He told us that you left
莎拉发来的邮件就走了
right after you got an e-mail from Sarah.
但你没回家  是吧
But you didn't go home, did you?
你去和她对质了
You went to go and confront her.
莎拉想要挽救她的婚姻
Sarah wanted to save her marriage.
她认为挽救的办法
She thought the way she could do that
就是让我在片场消失
was to get me out of the picture.
而你想让她再考虑一下
And you wanted to urge her to reconsider,
她不答应  你就杀了她
and when she didn't, you killed her.
我承认  我是去见那个贱人
I admit, I went to see the bitch.
我告诉她安琪拉·坎农是这部剧的灵魂人物
I told her Angela Cannon is the heart and soul of the show.
但我看出她不会退步之后  就离开了
But when I saw she wouldn't back down, I left.
-我不需要杀了她  -为什么
- I didn't need to kill her.  - And why is that?
因为我还有一手
Because I still had a hand to play.
每个人都以为《诱惑巷》剧组
Everybody thinks Sarah calls the shots
莎拉说了算
at "Temptation lane."
但二把手彼得·康纳利
But the second in command, Peter Connelly,
他才是电视台真正信任的人
he's the one the network really trusts.
你说你还有一手牌是什么意思
What is this other hand that you had to play?
我做了所有勤奋女演员都会做的事
I did what any industrious actress would do.
我从摄影棚直接去了他的公寓
I went to his apartment straight from the studio
然后利用我的魅力
and used my powers of persuasion
劝服他站在我这一边
to get him on my side.
你什么时候离开的
When did you leave?
天亮之后
The sun was up.
而我的角色还活着
And my character is still alive.
是的  她昨晚来我的公寓了
Yeah, she showed up at my apartment last night.
-她穿着一件裘皮大衣  -那又如何
- She was wearing a fur coat.  - So?
只穿了一件
Just...
裘皮大衣
a fur coat.
当她解开大衣时  我差点心脏病发
And I nearly had a heart attack when she let it slip open.
幻想了这么多年  她就在那儿
Years of fantasizing, and there she was,
-站在我面前  -她想要什么
- Standing right in front of me.  - And what did she want?
她对于莎拉
She was all fired up
把她的角色写死感到十分不满
about Sarah wanting to write her off the show.
所以之后我不得不听曼迪概括
So then I had to listen to Mandy summarize
每一篇赞扬她演技的《肥皂剧文摘》文章
every "Soap Digest" article praising her performance.
为了让她住嘴
Just to make her stop...
我答应会去找莎拉谈谈
I agreed that I would talk to Sarah.
只不过现在不用谈了
Only now you don't have to.
里斯  拿上笔记本电脑加入编剧组
Reese. Grab your laptop and join the group.
-大家都集合了  -你没开玩笑吗
- We're all hands on deck. - You mean it?
我不会问第二次的
I'm not gonna ask you twice.
你现在真是不惜冒险啊
Sounds like you're pretty desperate.
卡塞尔先生  你一年...出版一本书  是吗
Mr. Castle, you publish, what, one book a year?
差不多
Give or take.
同样是一年  我们要制作250集剧集
In that same time period, we produce 250 episodes.
我少了个编剧  里斯写了一些关于马的剧本
I'm down a writer. Reese wrote some script about horses
莎拉还挺喜欢的  没错
that Sarah actually liked, so, yeah,
就是新人我也不管了  我需要任何人手
I'm gonna take the extra help where I can get it.
当然除非你能屈尊来帮帮忙
Unless, of course, you'd like to jump in.
有趣的是  莎拉被杀害了
You know what's interesting? With Sarah out of the way,
曼迪就能留在剧中
Mandy gets to stay on the show,
-你也就能升职了  -拜托  我是专业人士
- and you get promoted. - Hey, I'm a professional.
曼迪留下来是因为安琪拉·坎农
Mandy's staying because Angela Cannon
是这部剧的灵魂人物
is the heart and soul of this show.
怎么听起来这么耳熟
Well, where have I heard that before?
我们保持联系
Uh, we'll keep in touch.
旅馆确认文斯的小冰箱上的
So the hotel confirmed that the time sensors
时间感应器一直到晚上11点都是开启的
in Vince's minibar were activated till 11:30 p.m.
那么看来致命的三角关系
So I guess our deadly love triangle
-没那么致命  -至少他的嫌疑排除了
- wasn't so deadly after all. - Not on his side anyway.
但是重要新闻是  莱恩查到了
But the hot news is, Ryan got a hit
莎拉那些神秘约会的线索
on those mystery appointments that Sarah was going to.
他找到了跟约会日期时间相匹配的
He found credit card charges that matched up time and date
-消费记录  -她去哪了
- to the meetings. - And where was she going?
去了第7街的咖啡馆  根据她的日程表
To a coffee shop on 7th and according to her calendar,
还有大约一个小时  就是她下次的赴约时间
her next meeting is in about an hour.
卡塞尔  喝咖啡休息下怎么样
Castle, you up for a coffee break?
-您的咖啡  -谢谢
- There you go. - Thanks.
我能帮什么忙啊
Can I help you?
是的  希望你帮得上
Yes. I hope so.
你认识这个女人吗
Do you recognize this woman?
是的
Yeah.
怎么了
Why?
她不能死  她不能死  不能啊
She can't be dead. She can't be dead. She can't.
很抱歉  戈德伯格女士
I'm so sorry, Ms. Goldberg.
这不公平  太不公平了
It's not fair. It is so not fair.
我该怎么办
What am I supposed to do?
你们两个关系很要好吗
Did the two of you know each other very well?
事实上  我跟她一点都不熟
Actually, I didn't know her at all.
那你为什么这么沮丧
Then why would you be so upset?
因为
Well, because...
她答应过看看我写的剧本
she promised she would read my screenplay,
如果她喜欢的话
And if she liked it...
她会帮我联系一名经纪人
she would help me find an agent.
她来这儿是跟谁见面
Who would she meet when she came here?
那还重要吗  她都死了
What's it matter? She's dead.
我的机会没了
I lost my chance.
我告诉你
I'll tell you what--
我跟你做个交易
I'll make you a deal.
如果你告诉我们发生了什么
If you tell us what happened after that,
我会读读你的剧本
I'll read your script,
如果我喜欢的话  我就把它交给我的经纪人
and if I like it, I'll give it to my agent.
真的吗
Really?
真的
Really.
她和一个男人见了面  他们坐在角落的那张桌
She met with a guy, and they sat at a table in a corner.
你还记得他长得什么样子吗
Do you remember what he looked like?
像他  一模一样
Um... like him. Exactly like him.
一杯双份的浓缩咖啡  好吗
Uh, give me a double espresso, will ya?
我的剧本怎么办
What about my script?
办完事我会回来拿的
I'll come back and get it when we're done.
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
我是莎拉·卡特勒的朋友
I'm a friend of Sarah Cutler.
是吗  钱带来了吗
Yeah? You bring my money?
什么钱
What money?
听着  我做了她让我做的事
Look, I did what she asked,
现在我要拿报酬
and now I want what I'm owed.
她让你干什么了
And, um, what is it that she asked you to do?
关你屁事  你到底是谁
None of your damn business. Who the hell are you?
纽约警局的
NYPD.
莎拉死了  这就是我的事
Sarah's dead, so it is my business.
你到底是谁
Now... who the hell are you?
强尼·戴姆斯  我是私家侦探
Johnny Dimes. I'm a PI.
莎拉·卡特勒是个客户  她死了是什么意思
Sarah Cutler was a client. What do you mean, she's dead?
"她死了"只有一个意思
"She's dead" only really has the one meaning.
她雇你调查她的丈夫吗
Did she hire you to follow her husband?
丈夫  不
Husband? No.
她雇我调查歌莉娅·钱伯斯
She hired me to investigate Gloria Chambers.
她妈妈
The mom.
我就知道  她是不是要器官移植
I knew it. Was she involved in organ harvesting?
那倒没有  但是我可以告诉你
That really didn't come up, but I can tell you this--
歌莉娅·钱伯斯不是她生母
Gloria Chambers isn't her real birth mom.
她是个冒牌货
She's a fake.
妈妈不是真正的妈妈
Ohh. The mom isn't really the mom?
案情不会比这更肥皂了
Does it get any soapier tn that?
那是私家侦探关于莎拉假妈妈的档案吗
Oh, Is that the P.I's file on Sarah's faux mother?
是啊  很显然歌莉娅三年前突然出现
Yeah, apparently Gloria showed up three years ago
声称她是莎拉的妈妈  莎拉起了怀疑
claiming to be Sarah's birth mom, and Sarah got suspicious.
于是她雇了私家侦探调查歌莉娅的底细
So she hired a p.I. in order to look into Gloria's history.
歌莉娅到底有什么阴谋诡计呢
What nefarious scheme has Gloria set into motion?
也许她打算
Perhaps she planned...
用一个克隆人替换莎拉
on replacing Sarah with a clone.
她想要莎拉的钱财
She wanted Sarah's money.
钱财
Money?
是啊  抱歉捅破了你的泡泡  卡塞尔
Yeah. Sorry to burst your bubble, Castle,
但是歌莉娅有过保险诈骗的案底
But Gloria's got a history of insurance scams
还有多个被骗光钱财的丈夫
and husbands with empty bank accounts.
-把她带过来了吗  -还在找她  发了全境通告
- We bringing her in? - Yeah, we're trying. We put out an APB.
公寓没有人
Her apartment's empty,
门卫说早上看到她提着箱子离开了公寓
and the doorman saw her leave with a suitcase this morning.
也许是戴姆斯告诉了莎拉关于歌莉娅的事
So maybe Dimes tells Sarah about Gloria,
莎拉跟她对质
Sarah confronts her,
之后歌莉娅为了防止暴露杀死了莎拉
and then Gloria kills sarah in order to avoid exposure.
然后在片场假扮伤心的母亲之后
And after playing the role of grieving mother on set,
歌莉娅知道情况不妙  就逃之夭夭了
Gloria knew enough to get the hell out of dodge.
看看是谁在肯尼迪机场
Yo. Look who got caught
想买飞往巴哈马的机票  被逮了正着
trying to buy a ticket to the Bahamas at J.F.K.
-歌莉娅  -纽约的一切都让我想起莎拉
- Gloria. - Everything in New York reminded me of Sarah.
我想让自己
I needed to distance myself
忘却她已离我而去的苦痛现实
from the agonizing truth that she's dead.
如果逃避是罪过的话
Now if denial is a crime...
我认罪
I plead guilty.
不错啊
Good to know.
谋杀的指控  你打算怎么办
Now how do you plead on murder?
歌莉娅·钱伯斯  也就是莎琳·塞勒斯
Gloria Chambers, also known as Charlene Sellars.
你真是个大忙人啊
You have been a very busy woman.
你还真是贫穷到富裕的典范啊
Yours is a real rags-to-riches story.
唯一的问题是  那些钱都不是你
Only trouble is, the riches never seem to be yours.
在福罗里达州诈骗
Fraud in Florida,
在北卡罗来纳州盗用公款
Embezzlement in North Carolina--
我为之前的那些误会都服过刑了
I served my time for those prior misunderstandings.
然后你找到了你的下一任"饭票"
And then you latched on to your next meal ticket--
康斯坦丁·皮瑞利
Constantine Pirelli.
在他之后是埃内斯托·克鲁兹
After him, it was Ernesto Cruz.
我听说他们很希望你能赶紧回去
I hear they're very anxious for you to come back...
把钱还给他们
with their money.
我跟他们结过婚  钱是我们的
I was married to those men. It was our money.
我可以告诉你
I can tell you,
每一分都是我辛苦赚来的
I earned every penny.
但是你每次都会把钱挥霍光  再寻觅
But as usual, you blew it all, and so you looked for
下一任"饭票"  于是你找上了莎拉·卡特勒
your next ticket, which you found in Sarah Cutler.
你在采访中听她提起
You heard an interview where she mentioned
她是被领养的  你做了点研究
being adopted, did a little research,
然后装成是她那失散多年的母亲
and then showed up as the long-lost mother.
莎拉的确有可能误以为
Sarah might have been under the impression
她是我女儿  但是我没有杀她
that she was my daughter, but I didn't kill her.
我是说  我以我自己的方式
I mean, in my own way, I was--
我其实挺喜欢莎拉的
I was fond of Sarah.
喜欢到假扮成她的妈妈
Fond enough that you were able to masquerade as her mother.
你有杀害她的动机
You had motive to kill her.
-所以你才会想逃出本土  -什么动机
- That's why you tried to flee the country. - What motive?
她的遗嘱显示她打算留给你30万美元
Her will shows she plan to leave you $300,000.
我的莎拉是个慷慨的孩子
Mm. She's a generous girl, my Sarah.
-她不是你的莎拉  -那也不是你的钱
- She's not your sarah. - And that's not your money.
你知道她把你写进了遗嘱
You knew she wrote you into her will.
事实上  这一切备不住都是你一手操控的
In fact, you probably planned it all along.
当她质问你的时候
When she confronted you,
你知道自己别无他法
you knew that you had a narrow window
只能在她揭穿你之前杀了她
within which to kill her before she wrote you out.
问题在于
Here's your problem--
我不是你们要找的凶手
I am not your killer.
如果我是你  我会查查她身边的那个男人
If I were you, I'd look into the other man in her life.
-哪个男人  -那个给了她
- What other man? - The one that gave her
两克拉亚瑟·克莱恩耳环的男人
the 2-karat Arthur Klein earrings just the other day.
你知道这个人的名字吗
Does this other man have a name?
莎拉没告诉我
Sarah didn't tell me that,
不管他是谁  他们肯定是刚刚分手
But whoever he was, they must have just split up,
因为他在试图赢回她的心
because he was trying to win her over.
不是吧  你把嫌疑指向一个神秘陌生人
Really? You're gonna point us to a mysterious stranger?
-这是事实  -出自一个职业骗子之口
- It's the truth. - Coming from a professional liar.
她死的时候  我根本不在这破烂的
I was nowhere near this godforsaken soap set
肥皂剧片场附近  我...
when she died. I...
我在利用闲暇做有用的事
I was doing something useful with my time.
给盲人读书吗
Reading to the blind.
差不多吧  我去捐钱了
Em, close. I was donating.
捐给小马驹[指赌马]
to the ponies.
歌莉娅钱包里的两张收据显示
The two receipts in Gloria's purse
下注时间是晚上10点
put a betting on races at 10 p. m..
死亡时间区的下限是晚上11点
And the time of death is estimated at 11:00 on the outside,
我们没有任何证据将她和摄影棚联系起来
and we don't have anything to tie her to the studio.
我原以为凶手肯定是假妈妈
I thought fake mom was a lock.
而且她的嫌疑越来越小
It's starting to look less that way by the minute.
我在莎拉的公寓发现了歌莉娅
I found the earrings that Gloria talked about
-说起的耳环  -高档货
- in Sarah's apartment. - Fancy.
是啊  超过一万块的高档货
Yeah, over 10 grand worth of fancy.
这值一万块
Those are worth over 10 grand?
-拜托  -蕾妮最爱钻石了
- Please. - Lanie loves diamonds.
"钻石恒久远  我对你的爱也是如此"
"Diamonds are forever like my devotion to you."
谁写得出这么肉麻的话
Who writes notes this cheesy?
反正不是她老公
Well, not the husband.
我查了他的财务支出  他没买过这个
I checked on his financials. He didn't buy them.
好吧  也许歌莉娅说的是事实
Okay, so maybe Gloria was telling us the truth.
也许莎拉也有外遇
Maybe Sarah was having an affair.
这就说得通了
Well, that makes perfect sense.
莎拉跟她的丈夫文斯分居了
Sarah was seperated from her husband Vince,
一天天繁杂枯燥的工作之后
and after long, grueling days at work,
她回到冰凉空荡的公寓
she'd go home to a cold, empty apartment.
感到寂寞和背叛  于是她在这个
Feeling lonely, betrayed, she seeks comfort
神秘男子的怀中寻求安慰
in the arms of this mystery man...
可她决定要挽回她的丈夫
And she decides that she wants her husband back,
所以写死了他的情妇曼迪·布朗森的角色
so writes his mistress, mandy Bronson, off the show
以求拯救他们的婚姻
in order to save their marriage.
她下一步要做的  就是摆脱这个男人
And her next stop would be to get rid of the other man.
所以也许是这个男人并不甘心放手  销声匿迹
So maybe the other man didn't go off quietly into the night.
我们不在的时候  你们练习接话吗
Do you two practice this when we're not around?
这对耳环只在
These earrings are exclusive
切尔西区的亚瑟·克莱恩精品店有售
to Arthur Klein's boutique in Chelsea.
去查查是谁买的
Let's find out who bought them.
现在歌莉娅没有嫌疑了
Okay, so Gloria is in the clear.
警员拿着她的照片在外围赌马场询问过
Uniforms showed her photo at O.T.B.,
一个酒保记得在11点一刻看见过她
and a bartender there remembers seeing her at 11:15.
我能明白她为什么中了歌莉娅的计
You know, I can see why she fell for gloria's con.
莎拉没有母亲  没有孩子
Sarah was motherless, childless.
她照料着年轻的编剧们
She was taking young writers under her wing.
-她在寻求亲情  -卡塞尔
- She was looking for family. - Wow, Castle.
这还真是很实际的推理啊
That's a refreshingly down-to-earth theory.
就是为了让你随时保持警觉
Just trying to keep you on your toes.
我们去查克莱恩的精品店的交易记录
Hey, so we ran down purchases at Klein's boutique,
猜猜查到了谁
and guess who popped.
-兰斯·哈斯丁  -这还没完
- Lance Hastings? - And that's not all.
我查了兰斯的信用卡记录
I ran Lance's credit card activity
以确定是他购买的
to confirm the purchase
结果另有发现
and something else caught my eye.
兰斯在谋杀案发生当晚叫了一辆出租车
Lance charged a cab ride to the studio
载他去了摄影棚
the night of the murder.
是啊  我们询问他的时候
Yeah, when we interviewed him,
他说他6点就直接回家了
he said he went straight home at 6:00 p.m.
出租车公司的车8点载他回了摄影棚
Cab company drove him back to the studio around 8:00.
这个时间刚好在我们推算的死亡时间区内
Okay, so that falls right within the window of our time of death.
把他带过来
Go pick him up.
我们派了警员过去
Yeah, we already sent a uniform.
他不在家  也不接电话
He's not home, and he's not answering his phone.
我母亲之前在片场跟他聊过
My mother was speaking to him earlier on set.
嗨宝贝  奶奶在吗  我要跟她说话
Hi, sweetie. Is gram there? I need to talk to her.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我知道凶手在哪
I know where the killer is.
他跟我妈在一起
He's with my mother.
卡塞尔  没事的
Castle, it's okay.
我确定你妈妈没有危险
I'm sure your mom's not in any danger.
是啊  你大概是对的
Yeah, you're probably right.
我很抱歉  亲爱的
I'm sorry, my dear,
但在我把一切都告诉你之后
but after everything I've told you,
我不能让你活着离开这个房间
I can't let you leave this room alive.
兰斯  好好想想你要做的事
Lance, think about what you're doing.
我正想着呢
I am thinking about it.
-我不能留你活口  -想想我们...
- I can't let you live! - Think about us--
-把刀放下  -什么
- Drop the knife! - What--
-放下武器  -等等
- Drop the weapon. - W-w-w-wait a minute.
理查德  你在做什么
Richard, what are you doing?
没什么  救你的命而已
Oh, nothing. Just saving your life. That's all.
她说把刀放下
She said drop the knife!
这刀唯一能切的东西  就是黄油
The only thing that knife could kill is butter.
你们说什么呢
What are you talking about?
这是个道具
It's a prop.
我们是在排演一出戏
We were just working out a scene.
各位  这完全是我的主意
Guys, it was completely my idea.
演员版的"教我怎么挥高尔夫球杆"
You know, the actor's version of "Show me your golf swing."
这把刀也许是假的
Well, the knife may be fake,
但是你插进莎拉后背的斧子是真的
but the ax you put into Sarah's back was real.
你对莱恩警探和埃斯波西托警探撒谎
You lied to detectives Ryan and Esposito
没有坦诚交代凶案当晚你的去处
regarding your whereabouts the night of the murder.
你想知道真相
You want the truth?
你解释一下会比较好
That would be a great place to start.
真相你们接受不了
You can't handle the truth.
先生  我对你模仿杰克·尼科尔森
Sir, I am not interested in your
不感兴趣
Jack Nicholson impressions.
我们知道你在案发当晚
We know that you went back to the studio
回到了摄影棚
the night of the murder.
而我要问的是  你回去干什么了
And what I'm asking is why.
只是进行同事间友好的对话
It was a friendly conversation between colleagues.
在这个友好对话中  她告诉你
A friendly conversation in which she told you
她要回到她丈夫身边
she was going to go back to her husband.
你们到底在说什么啊
What the hell are you talking about?
-她为什么说这个  -因为她在跟你分手
- Why would she do that? - Because she was breaking up with you.
你们以为是这么回事吗
Is that what you think is going on here?
你们以为莎拉和我是情人关系吗
You think that sarah and I were lovers?
你有没有
Did you or did you not
送过她一副昂贵的钻石耳环
buy an expensive pair of diamond earrings for her?
送过  但不是为了取悦她
Yes, but not to woo her.
这是为了让莎拉同意让我
It was to encourage Sarah
-在合约之外接拍一部电影  -演电影
- to let me out of my contract for a movie role. - Movie role?
没错  科恩兄弟邀请我参演
Yes. The Coen Brothers have asked me to play
马特·达蒙新片里的脑残老爸
Matt Damon's half-wit dad in their new movie.
这角色简直是一生才碰到一次
It's a role of a lifetime.
非常有被颁奖礼提名的范儿
It has nominations written all over it.
这也解释不了
That still doesn't explain
当晚你为何回到片场
why you went back to the studio that night.
我去当面感谢莎拉
I went to thank Sarah in person,
因为我的经纪人打电话给我
because my agent called me
说她同意我演那电影
that evening to tell that she'd agreed to let me out.
我之所以之前没说
The reason that I didn't mention any of it is
是因为我不想冒险失去拍电影的机会
that I didn't wanna risk missing work on the movie.
你为何不直接打给她
Why didn't you just call her?
我想让她知道我有多感激
I wanted her to know how much I appreciated it.
所以你回去感谢她  仅此而已
So you went back to thank her, and that's it?
不  也不尽然
No, not exactly. Uh...
我到那儿的时候  她在读一份剧本
when I got there, she was reading a script,
看起来很难过
and she seemed upset.
我问她为什么
I asked her why, and...
她说有人背叛了她
she said somebody had betrayed her.
-是谁  -起初我以为是我
- Who? - Well, at first, I thought it was me
因为接演了电影  但是后来
for taking the movie role, but then...
她说  是有人并非
she said that someone wasn't who...
如她想的那样
she thought they were.
她没具体说这个人是谁吗
And she didn't let on as to who this person was?
没有  我不想让她
No. I didn't want to give her the opportunity
在电影的事情上改变主意
to change her mind about the movie,
所以退场了  从舞台左侧
So I exited... stage left.
好了  找到了莎拉签署的
Okay. Found the deal memo that Sarah signed
让兰斯出演电影的合同备忘了
in order to get Lance out for his movie.
他没在撒谎
He wasn't lying.
我妈绝对饶不了我
My mother is never gonna let me forget this.
拜托  卡塞尔  她可能在想
Oh, come on, Castle. She'll probably think
你这么关心她  真是贴心呢
it was sweet that you were concerned about her.
我们说的可是玛莎·罗杰斯
This is Martha Rodgers we are talking about.
我破坏了属于她的"时刻"
I intruded on her "Moment."
不  我会付出惨痛代价的
No, I will pay dearly.
兰斯来的时候  莎拉告诉他
When Lance came here, Sarah told him
有人并非她想的那样
that someone wasn't who she thought they were.
你觉得那说的是谁
Who do you think that was?
那个把我妈衬托的跟圣徒一样的女人
How about the woman who makes my mother look like a saint?
没错  但是莎拉已经把歌莉娅踢出她的生活了
Yeah, but Sarah already cut Gloria out of her life.
也许  也许是她偷情的丈夫
Maybe... maybe it was her cheating husband.
可是兰斯是在曼迪·布朗森之后跟莎拉见得面
Except Lance met with Sarah after Mandy Bronson.
曼迪出现的时候  莎拉已经决定
By the time Mandy showed up, Sarah had already decided
要挽回自己的婚姻了
what she wanted to do with her marriage.
是啊  但就算莎拉打定主意
Yeah, but even if Sarah decided
她要跟文斯重归于好
that she was gonna get back together with Vince,
也不表示她就没有疑问
it doesn't mean that she didn't have doubts.
没错  你说得对
No. No, you're right.
可他有不在场证明
Except he has an alibi.
每个人都有不在场证明
Everyone has an alibi.
好吧  有人没有
Yeah, well, somebody out there doesn't,
我们会找到的
And we are gonna find them.
也许我们该睡一觉想一想
Well, maybe we should sleep on it.
各睡各的
Separately.
凯瑟琳·贝克特  我可是绅士
Katherine Beckett, I never.
女士们好啊
Hello, ladies.
嗨  老爸  奶奶告诉我
Hey, dad. Gram told me
你是怎么在她的约会上充英雄的
how you went all Jason Bourne on her date.
拜托  危难时我所展现的大无畏精神
Come on. I think I deserve some kudos for my selfless courage
应该得到嘉奖才对嘛
in the face of perceived danger.
随你怎么想
Ah, think what you will.
但我已经自作主张选好了道歉礼物
But I've taken the liberty of selecting an apology gift--
47页  帮你折了页
Page 47, dog-eared for your convenience.
-这条裙子  -对  还有这双鞋
- The dress? - Uh-huh. And the shoes.
对了  还有这个包包
Oh! And the purse.
儿子  这个是哪儿来的
Where did you get this, darling?
办案认识的一个女的
Oh, from a woman I met on the case.
很有抱负的一位编剧
She's an aspiring writer.
我一心软就答应给她看看
In a moment of weakness, I told her I'd read it.
写得很不错  角色鲜明
Oh, it's really pretty good. She's got very vivid characters,
情节合理  还很重口味哦
Well plotted, pleasantly salacious.
正好  我就这么跟她说
Great. That's what I'll tell her.
那可不行  你答应人家你会看  是你
No, no, no, no. You said you would read it, honey. You.
我看行了吧
I will.
不过我还得再琢磨一下
I just have to do a little
-这个案子  -他分明是在拖延
- more thinking on the case. - He's procrastinating.
-我知道  -不是拖延
- I know. I know. - No, I am not.
最关键的谜团快真相大白了
I am just about to solve a critical piece of our mystery.
你确定兰斯不是斧头杀手了吧
Now that you've determined that Lance is not the ax murderer?
老爸  那最关键的证据是什么
So what's the critical piece of evidence, dad?
莎拉·卡特勒被害前
Well, shortly before she died,
说有人背叛她
Sarah Cutler said that someone had betrayed her.
我判断那个人就是凶手
I think that person is our killer.
儿子  这么说的话谁都有可能
Well, then it could be anybody, darling,
背叛可是肥皂剧的经典桥段
because betrayal is a way of life on a soap opera.
就说《诱惑巷》吧
And let me tell you, "Temptation lane"
整个一贪婪
is like this seething cauldron
背叛和野心的大杂烩
of sordidness and treachery and naked ambition.
你知道什么样的人
And you know which people
最有控制欲  最阴险狡诈吗
are the most manipulative and devious?
知道
I do.
我知道背叛莎拉的是谁了
I know who betrayed Sarah.
合同里面没说
Look, there's nothing in my contract
突然要我演警察呀
that says that I have to be a cop all of a sudden.
我这边有彩排
I-I--I've gotta rehearse.
别打了  开拍吧  快点
Get off the phone. Let's do this. Let's go.
-行了 卡塞尔  走吧  -等会儿
- Okay, Castle. Let's go. - Oh, wait.
别急  等会儿  这可是我的肥皂剧处女编
No, hang on. I just wrote my first soap scene,
快要拍了
which they are about to shoot.
没事  我看电视就行  得去抓人了
Well, I'll--I'll catch it on TV. We've got an arrest to make.
不用去了  等着  这场戏会让凶手现形
No, no, wait. This scene is going to expose the killer.
唯在戏剧中  我等方能窥见
"The play's the thing wherein we'll catch
王的本心  引自《哈姆雷特》
the conscience of the king"-- Hamlet.
我们已经知道凶手是谁了
We already know who the killer is,
你这是浪费时间  引自我的语录
so you're wasting my time-- me.
我要是能让她认罪呢
Not if I get us a confession.
-各就就位  -开拍了  快去看
- Places, please. - They're starting. Let's go.
好的  不  送回来
Okay. No, send it back.
对  好的  谢谢
Yeah. All right, thanks.
-二位请进  -谢谢
- Hey, come on in, guys. - Thanks.
卡塞尔  这是干...
Castle, what are we--
嘘  别说话  看了就明白
Ah-- shh, shh. Just watch, just watch.
请把对着摄影机的那扇门关上
Can we close the downstage door
我们好聚焦在曼迪身上
to get better eyes on Mandy,
好吗
Please?
清场  好了  大家注意  请保持安静
Clear the set. Here we go, everybody. Quiet on the set.
五  四
In five... Four...
三  二
Three... Two...
二号机准备
Two's on the line.
你不能敲下门吗  我在换衣服
Can't you at least knock? I'm changing.
该见的都见了
Nothing I haven't seen before...
而且还余味悠长
and enjoyed immensely.
真扯
Really?
肥皂剧嘛  我得按套路来
It's a soap opera. I had to honor the form.
乔瑟夫  你来干嘛
What are you doing here, Joseph?
-如果是为了我们的关系  -不是
- If this is about our relationship-- - no, it isn't.
是关于你的研究论文
It's about your research paper.
就是我让你投递申请
The one I had you submit
马尼古记者奖学金的那篇
for the Montenegro journalism fellowship.
有消息说谁胜出了吗
Is there news about the winner?
这个奖学金可以
The thing about the fellowship is that
为你打通门路  帮你开展事业
it can open doors, it launches careers.
所以我才推荐了你
That's why I recommended you.
-切到一号镜头  -那我赢了吗
- Over to one. - So did I win?
三号镜头
Three.
我今天早上去咖啡馆
I went to the coffee shop this morning,
有个店员请我看一下
and a barista there asked me to read an article
她的大学作业
that she had written for her college paper.
奇怪的是  居然和你的一模一样
Oddly enough, it was identical to yours.
-肯定是误会了  -不是误会
- There must be some mistake. - No,
就是你交上去那篇  你以为
just the one you made in assuming that you could
别人的东西能被这样占为己有吗
pass off somebody else's material as your own.
安琪拉  你是个骗子
You are a fraud, Angela.
我要打电话告诉奖学金委员会
And I am going to call the fellowship
让他们知道你的真面目
and let them know that exactly.
对了  还有
Oh, and by the way...
你被解雇了
you're fired.
卡  大家演得不错
And cut. Nice job, people.
我有点不明白  这个...
I don't understand. This is--
这好像不是我们昨天讨论的剧本
This is not the scene that we worked on yesterday.
做了一些调整
We made some adjustments.
不过  这场景应该似曾相识吧
And yet, it has an oddly familiar ring to it.
你的工作之一就是读别人的剧本
Reading other people's scripts is a part of your job,
-是吧  -你到底想说我什么
- isn't it? - What are you accusing me of?
没看这场戏吗  想要成为一名编剧
Did you not see the scene? If you're going to be a writer,
你要更能听懂潜台词才行
you have to have a better grasp of subtext.
我...
Look, I--I'm...
我可能是借用了别人的剧本
I might have mixed up some of the scripts,
但是莎拉死的那晚
but I was at the fellowship mixer
我在奖学金联谊会上
the night that Sarah died.
没人记得晚上8点以后见过你
Nobody there remembers seeing you after 8:00 P.M.
里斯  凶手用斧子砍死了莎拉
Sarah was killed with an ax, reese.
不管是谁杀的  凶手的身上鞋上
Whoever killed her got blood on their clothes
肯定会沾上血迹
and on their shoes.
有些血迹肉眼看不到
Some of it invisible to the naked eye,
但是不管你怎么洗它
but it doesn't matter how much you try to wash it,
还是洗不掉
it's still there.
我已经派警员到你公寓去了
I have officers at your apartment.
你们根本不知道
You have no idea
我为她做了多少事
what I did for her.
给她照顾宠物狗
Picking up her dogs,
给她取干洗的衣服
picking up her dry cleaning,
不管深夜还是周末都要上班
The late nights, the weekends,
还没有假期
no vacation.
你有本事试试在这么忙的情况下写个剧本啊
You try writing a script with all of that going on.
我累死累活
I worked too hard
我不能放弃这个机会啊
to let it end that way.
那个机会是我应得的
I deserved that opportunity,
我不能让她把这个机会夺走
and I could not let her take that away from me.
这个机会从一开始就不属于你
It was never yours to begin with.
杀莎拉就为了剽窃不被发现吗
Killing Sarah to keep a lid on her plagiarism?
-真是残忍啊  -动机倒是很常见
- That's cold. - And pretty ordinary as far as motives go.
不想脚踏实地工作
She didn't want to put in the work,
-光想走捷径  -写作路上无捷径
- so she took a shortcut. - There are no shortcuts in writing.
是没有  但去咱们最喜欢的酒吧可以抄近路哦
Nope, but there is to our favorite bar.
我发现一条去"老地方"的新路线
I found a new route that'll get us
8分钟就能到
to the Old Haunt in eight minutes.
想喝啤酒吗  走吧  我认识老板
You up for a beer? Come on. I know the owner.
行  我去  那你呢  卡塞尔
Yeah, I'm down, bro. How 'bout you, Castle?
随后就到
Right behind you.
怎么了
What?
给你份礼物
Got you a present.
《诱惑巷》卡司的签名照
A signed cast photo from "Temptation Lane."
你从哪儿弄的
How did you even get this?
我认识有门路的人
I know people who know people.
好吧
Okay.
我九岁的时候
I was 9,
扁桃体被摘除了
and I had to get my tonsils taken out,
当时很痛苦
and I was miserable.
所以妈妈就请假
and so my mom took time off of work
留在家陪我
and... stayed with me
她拥着我坐在沙发上看电视
and cuddled up in front of the TV on the couch,
当时看的就是《诱惑巷》
and we would watch episodes of "Temptation Lane."
所以每次看这部剧  总是...
So every time I see it now, it just--
总会让我觉得温馨  觉得安全
it makes me feel like home and...safe.
说完了  开始点评吧
So there you go. Judge away.
我的DVR
My DVR...
会把你的DVR衬托的跟"杰作剧场"一样
would make yours look like "Masterpiece theatre."
但还是很高兴能知道这些你的故事
But I am glad to know this about you.
那我先走了
I'll leave you to it.
卡塞尔  谢谢你送的照片
Hey, Castle. Thank you for the photo.
回见
I'll see you.
你好
Hey.
过了这么多年
After all these years,
很多次本可以拥你入怀
all the times I could've been holding you in my arms...
那就不要浪费时间说话了
Then let's not waste more time with words.
让我们的双唇来倾诉情思
let's just let our lips do the talking.
你们俩又在对台词吗
You two running lines again?
噢  不是
Oh. Well, no, no.
我们只是...  聊天而已
We were just, uh... you know, talking.
我得...
Um... I'm gonna--
我要...
I'll just--I'll...
去...
go to the...